Finding Aid for Michigan Wolverine Student Cooperative (University of Michigan) records, 1932-1943
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Wolverine Student Cooperative (University of Michigan) records 1932-1943
Michigan Wolverine Student Cooperative (University of Michigan)
2 linear feet and 1 outsize item
87246 Bimu F54 2 F54 Outsize
Records, 1932-1943, of the Michigan Cooperative Boarding House of the University of Michigan, a cooperative eating club for students that was reorganized in 1937 as the Michigan Wolverine Student Cooperative. Include minutes, reports, correspondence, financial records and print materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received in multiple accessions from different individuals and organizations (donor nos. 566, 1384, 2942 and 2882 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
Organized in 1932 as a cooperative eating club for students, the Michigan Cooperative Boarding House was reorganized in 1937 as the Michigan Wolverine Student Co-op. A historical sketch is included in the records.
The records are organized in two main series: Records of the Michigan Cooperative Boarding House and Records of the Michigan Wolverine Student Cooperative, both of which comprise minutes, reports, correspondence and financial records. A third series, Miscellaneous, comprises a single oversize print of a tree of knowledge.
Subjects:
Cooperative societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1931-1940.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1941-1950.; Michigan Wolverine Student Cooperative (University of Michigan)
- Records of Michigan Cooperative Boarding House
  - Minutes, 1932-1934, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Constitution (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Audit, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Historical Sketch, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Records of Michigan Wolverine Student Cooperative, Inc.
  - Minutes, 1937-1940, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Newsletter, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and Bylaws (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1937-1944 and undated, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Manual of the Accounting System (Box 1)
  - Financial Reports, 1937-1942, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Summary Payroll Sheets, 1940-1942 (Box 1)
  - Notes Payable to Sponsors (Box 1)
  - Cash Recapitulation, 1941-1942 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Reports, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Financial Ledgers, 1938-1943, 6 volumes (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Tree of Knowledge, (Outsize Print (Box 2)